Gabbott family papers, 1908-1963 M2009
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Gabbott family papers
1908-1963
1920s-1960s
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Gabbott, Parry
Gabbott, Frank R.
Gabbott, Cecil P.
Gabbott, Bernard L.
Gabbott family
M2009
1 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Biographical / Historical
Brothers Bernard Lee Gabbott, Cecil Parr Gabbott, and Francis (Frank) Ridyard Gabbott were the youngest children of Edward Ridyard Gabbott and Ellen Gabbott. The three settled abroad as export brokers and businessmen in China. Frank was a partner and the Managing Director of the import-export company Gabbott, Begg, & Co., Ltd which was incorporated in Hong Kong, and was also involved in F.R. Gabbott & Company. Bernard was in partnership with his brother Frank as a financial and purchasing administrator for F.R. Gabbott & Company. Cecil appears to have been an administrator in the Property Department of Palmer & Turner Architects, Surveyors and Civil Engineers, based in Hong Kong, and later established the firm C.P. Gabbott and Partners. Their eldest brother, [Edgar] Parry Gabbott, settled in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, and he, too, established some sort of commercial enterprise abroad.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist primarily of correspondence from the four Gabbott brothers to their mother Mrs. [Ellen] Gabbott, and to their sister [Eleanor] Mabel Gabbott, both in Leytonstone, UK. Comprises 77 letters (mostly sent from Hong Kong and Shanghai), approximately 10 marine insurance policies for large cargos of goods being exports from China to England, some correspondence related to the shipments, and a small assortment of personal photographs. A few letters are from Ruby Gabbott (Frank's wife) and Ethel Gabbott (Cecil's wife). The collection gives insight into trade between Britain and China in the first half of the 20th century. The correspondence includes commentary on an array of subjects such as communism in China, the Chinese Civil War, general living conditions in Hong Kong, financial affairs, and inter-personal matters. Also included are a few miscellaneous letters from Dermot Spencer and R. G. Spencer of Surrey's Windmill Press, (William Heinemann Publishers) to Elizabeth Wheeler Schermerhorn, author of "Malta of the Knights" and others.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase; 2014. Accession MSS 2014-031.
China -- Commerce -- Great Britain -- History; Great Britain -- Commerce -- China -- History; Gabbott, Parry; Gabbott, Frank R.; Gabbott, Cecil P.; Gabbott, Bernard L.; Gabbott family
- Insurance company invoices of goods shipped, 1930's. (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
- Frank Gabbott correspondence, 1908-1937, Shanghai (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Sister Ruby Gabbott (Franks' wife?) correspondence, 1934-1935, Shanghai (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bernard Gabbott correspondence, 1925-1960, Hong Kong (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bernard Gabbott correspondence and photographs, 1961-1963, Hong Kong (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Parry Gabbott correspondence, 1921-1952, Philadelphia (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Frank Gabbott correspondence, 1952-1961, Hong Kong and one from Vancouver (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cecil Gabbott correspondence, 1922-1937, Shanghai (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Windmill Press letters, Kingswood, Tadworth, Surrey, 1928-1930 and n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous letters, 1923-1953 and n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Ethel Gabbott (Cecil's wife) correspondence, 1924-1926, Shanghai (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Ethel Gabbott (Cecil's wife), correspondence,1924-1926, Shanghai (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Photographs (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Nitrate negs (Half-box 3)